# IJEOMA EMERUWA

Front End Developer

# **Personal Info**

**Address** 

2, Okemesi Crescent, Garki 2, Abuja

**Phone** 

08121383634

E-mail

helloijeoma@gmail.com

**GitHub** 

github.com/ijeomaemeruwa

**WWW** 

helloijeoma.com

LinkedIn

linkedin.com/in/ijeoma-emeruwa

# **Skills**

HTML, CSS and Javascript

Git

React

Firebase and Netlify

Communication

Team work

Ensuring code is scalable, redable and responsive

Google

#### **Interests**

Open source software

Technical writing

Research

## References

Available on request.

A front end developer with one year experience possessing skills which involve translating design mockups to front end code, writing maintinable cross-browser code, ensuring code is readable, scalable and responsive, and communicating with RESTful web services to add back end data and functionality to an application.

## **Experience**

2020-10 -

## **Front End Developer**

present

Kanban App Project

- Developed a productivity board that incorporates the agile software development process and aims to improve time management and collaboration using react and context API.
- Source code: https://github.com/ijeomaemeruwa/kanban\_app
- Status: In development

2020-06 -

present

### **Mobile Web Specialist**

Google Africa Developer Scholarship (Google, Andela)

- Utilized resources provided by Pluralsight to learn front end technologies, build websites using HTML, CSS and Javascript, and improve my collaboration skills using Git version control and Github.
- Skill IQ 248: https://app.pluralsight.com/score/skill-assessment/html-css-javascript/summary?context=profile

#### **Front End Developer**

Compact App Project

- Developed a client side application that uses javascript ES6+ concepts to upload and save resources via url links.
- Integrated a backend as a service (firebase) to persist data to the DOM when offline and save files to firebase firestore database.
- Source code: https://github.com/ijeomaemeruwa/compact-app

#### **Front End Developer**

BookClub App

- Built a user interface with react and integrated RESTful web services that utilizes react hooks to manage state and fetch data from the API to render provided data to the browser using JavaScript ES6+ array methods.
- Source code: https://github.com/ijeomaemeruwa/bookclub

# **Education**

2020-08 -

#### **Havard University Online**

present

• CS50: Introduction to Computer Science

2020-05 -

#### **Udemy**

present

 Complete React Developer course (with Redux, Hooks, Context API and Firebase)

2019-10

# **The Odin Project**

Full StacK JavaScript

2012-02 -

# **University of Lagos**

2017-02

Bachelor of Medical Laboratory Science